<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Rohrbach Science</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Rohrbach Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Theme</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 15:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/hugo/</guid>
      <description>The whole reason that this webite exists is to give me a toy to play with! I wanted to understand how hugo works, so I made my own Hugo theme.
GitHub Link coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy is Made Up: Interesting Conceptual Discussions around Energy and its Definition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/energy/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Talk given at the Fall Meeting of the Indiana Section of AAPT in Sept, 2020.
Abstract Following the derivation of kinetic and potential energy formulas in the Giancolli textbook, I have been stressing to my students in recent years that energy is a made-up concept, and that&amp;ndash;in principle&amp;ndash;it is not necessary for building a coherent model of interactions between objects. I discuss how energy is nothing more than a helpful &amp;ldquo;bookkeeping method&amp;rdquo; for multi-object systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diaper Tracker</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/diaper-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/diaper-tracker/</guid>
      <description>When my first daughter was born, we were asked by the doctor to track her feedings and her wet and dirty diapers. While there are apps that do this, they are all too complicated! So I did the only logical thing: coded my own simpler app from scratch! This &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; is a collection of php scripts hosted on a Raspberry Pi on my local network. It simply allows you to keep timestamps of &amp;lsquo;poop&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;pee&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;feed&amp;rsquo; events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holograms: The Boundary Between Geometric and Wave Optics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/holograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/holograms/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the Spring Meeting of the Indiana Section of AAPT in April, 2019.
Abstract We will use the geometric definition of a parabola to explore the properties of concave and convex mirrors. We will then expand this discussion to explore the properties of a hyperbolic mirror. Finally, we will demonstrate how a holography takes advantage of the hyperbolic nature of wave interference in order to construct what is essentially a geometric phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/rpi/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to find something useful to do with the GPIO pins on a Raspberry Pi. Haven&amp;rsquo;t found anything useful to do yet, but I have played around with a few non-useful things!
 Controlling LED&amp;rsquo;s (with Python and with php through a hosted web server) Controlling a Stepper Motor 7-segment Display Counter and Timer  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating Literacy without Giving up your Physics Curriculum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/literacy/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the Spring Meeting of the Indiana Section of AAPT in April, 2018.
Abstract There&amp;rsquo;s been a schoolwide push at Avon for increased cross-curricular literacy instruction that I have long tried to ignore because I was afraid of the time it would take away from the physics curriculum. However, over the past two years I&amp;rsquo;ve hit upon some strategies that not only foster literacy skills in students but also seem to increase the interest-level and quality of classroom discussion about physics topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation of Intellectual Momentum: Staying connected to the field of physics even if your job doesn&#39;t make you</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/intellectual-momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/intellectual-momentum/</guid>
      <description>I gave this talk to the Physics Department at Wabash College (my alma mater) in October, 2014.
Abstract I had always known that I wanted to teach, but as I prepared to graduate from Wabash, I was hesitant to follow through on that plan. My four years of studying physics had opened my mind to a way of thinking I had grown to love and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up. Would teaching provide the same intellectual stimulation I had enjoyed in college?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ledger &amp; HLedger Scripts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/ledger/</guid>
      <description>I use Plain-Text Accounting and the command line tools Ledger and HLedger in order to track family finances. I have written these scripts to help me import data from monthly bank statements into my ledger file and visualize our finances.
GitHub Link coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GlowScript Animations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/glowscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/glowscript/</guid>
      <description>During the 2017 INAAPT Spring Meeting, I listened to a talk about GlowScript as a way to create VPython animations online. I created the following projects just to fool around.
 Doppler Effect Animation (bug jumping on water) Monkey &amp;amp; Hunter Animation Bouncing Ball Animation (My first animation, and just an attempt to understand how to code free fall) Waves on a spring (This was an experiment to see if I could explore a wave as a collection of particles that only interact with neighboring particles instead of as a continuous entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using 3D Glasses to Tie Together Ray Optics, Wave Optics, and Color Mixing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/3d-glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/3d-glasses/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the Spring Meeting of the Indiana Section of AAPT in April, 2016.
Links  PowerPoint Slides (.pptx)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A priori which-way information in quantum interference with unstable particles</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/a-priori-which-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/a-priori-which-way/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2010, I had the opportunity to work with Dr. Dennis Krause at Wabash College on a project he was considering attempting a theoretical treatment of interference of quantum unstable particles (QuUP). This publication eventually came out of this project.
Abstract If an unstable particle used in a two-path interference experiment decays before reaching a detector, which-way information becomes available that reduces the detected interference fringe visibility V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest for Uncertainty: Recovering an Appreciation for Truth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/quest-for-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/quest-for-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally written for my undergraduate Philosophy of Education course with Dr. Sam Rocha. It grew into a publication and presentation for the Society for the Philosophical Study of Eduction.
Abstract In this modern age, we place much faith in our scientists and their supposed objectivity. On the other hand, we are often seduced by the subjectivity found in cultural and moral relativism. Caught between these two seemingly antithetical conceptions, it is difficult to sort out what this thing called ‘Truth’ is, how closely we can know it, and whether it even exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the equivalence principle with unstable particles</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/equivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/equivalence/</guid>
      <description>In the summer of 2010, I had the opportunity to work with Dr. Dennis Krause at Wabash College on a project he was considering attempting a theoretical treatment of interference of quantum unstable particles (QuUP). This publication eventually came out of this project.
Abstract We develop a framework to test the equivalence principle under conditions where the quantum aspects of nature cannot be neglected, specifically in the context of interference phenomena with unstable particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Exit Velocity of a Compressed Air Cannon</title>
      <link>http://example.org/publications/exit-velocity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/publications/exit-velocity/</guid>
      <description>During my junior year at Wabash College, we built a compressed air cannon as part of my Advanced Lab Course. This publication came out of work on this cannon.
Abstract The use of compressed air cannons in an undergraduate laboratory provides a way to illustrate the connection between diverse physics concepts, such as conservation of momentum, the work-kinetic energy theorem, gas expansion, air drag, and elementary Newtonian mechanics. However, it is not clear whether the expansion of the gas in the cannon is an adiabatic or an isothermal process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
